MICHAEL ILIADIS

CONTACT Information 2145Sheridan Road, Rm. M472

Northwestern University Email: miliad@u.northwestern.edu

Evanston, IL 60208-3118 http://users.eecs.northwestern.edu/~mif365

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie on variety of research topics in the field of Computer Vision including Face Recognition, Image Retrieval, Sparse Representations and Compressive Sensing. I am a member of the Image & Video Processing Laboratory group under the supervision of Professor Aggelos K. Katsaggelos.

Cellular: (408) 886-0912

EDUCATION

Northwestern University, EVANSTON, ILLINOIS

09/2011 - PRESENT

- Ph.D. student, Department of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science
- Advisor: Professor Aggelos K. Katsaggelos

University of Bath, BATH, UK

09/2008 - 09/2009

- MSc, Department of Computer Science
- Thesis: Automatic Optimisation of Data Structures for Client-Server Computing

University of Piraeus, PIRAEUS, GREECE

09/2003 - 06/2008

- BSc, Department of Digital Systems
- Thesis: Discrete Event Modeling and Simulation of a Call Center

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Northwestern University

EVANSTON, ILLINOIS, U.S.A

09/2011 - Present

- Research on Sparse Representations for Face Recognition and high-dimension signals.

University of Piraeus

Research assistant

Piraeus, Greece

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

09/2009 - 12/2010

- Collaboration in research into the Digital Divide using multivariate statistical methods.

Professional Experience

TCL Research America

San Jose, California, USA 06/2014 - 09/2014

Research Intern

- Researching and developing the face recognition problem. Our novel method combines the sparsity-based approaches with additional least-squares steps and exhibits robustness to outliers achieving significant performance improvement with little additional cost.

TCL Research America

San Jose, California, USA

RESEARCH INTERN

06/2013 - 09/2013

- Researching and developing a large-scale video retrieval system. Novel fingerprinting features were introduced to improve recognition rate and speed of the matching process. The recognition rate of the system was improved by 5% over the state-of-the-art.

IT Support Center of the Greek Army (KEPYES) SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MINISTRY OF DEFENSE, GREECE 09/2010 - 05/2011

- Designing and implementing large-scale software in Java using web services. In particular, I implemented a distributed auto-update system for stand-alone applications which allows an efficient and fast distribution of new versions of an app.

GRADUATE COURSEWORK

EXPERIENCE

Digital Signal Processing (Pappas)

Teaching University of Piraeus

TA OF PROF. JOHN PARAVANTIS

PIRAEUS, GREECE 11/2009 - 12/2009

Computer Skills

• Programming Languages: Java (expert), C, Matlab, Ruby on Rails

• Java SE (Java Applets, Java Sockets, JFC/Swing) and Java EE (Servlets, JSP)

• Web Technologies: HTML, XML, CSS, Web Services

Professional Service • Reviewer: ICME 2014, ICME 2015

TECHNICAL

Member of Human Perception in Multimedia Computing (since 2013).

ACTIVITIES Member of Greek Computer Society (since 2009).

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Greek: native English: fluent

PUBLICATIONS

Michael Iliadis, Leonidas Spinoulas, Albert S. Berahas and Aggelos K. Katsaggelos. Sparse Representation and Least Squares-Based Classification in Face Recognition *European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO)*, Lisbon, Portugal, September 2014.

Michael Iliadis, Jeremy Watt, Leonidas Spinoulas and Aggelos K. Katsaggelos. Video Compressive Sensing using Multiple Measurement Vectors. *IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)*, Melbourne, Australia, September 2013. **Top 10% Paper Recognition**

Michael Iliadis, Seunghwan Yoo, Xin Xin and Aggelos K. Katsaggelos. Virtual Touring: A Content Based Image Retrieval Application. *In IEEE Int. Conf. on Multimedia & Expo (ICME)*, San Jose, CA, July 2013.

Michael S. Iliadis and John A. Paravantis. A Multivariate Cross-Country Empirical Analysis of the Digital Divide. *In Proceedings of the sixteenth IEEE Symposium on Computers and Communications*, June 2011.

PATENTS

Michael Iliadis, Haohong Wang. Face Recognition System and Method. US Patent app. 20141208. November 2014.

Michael Iliadis, Haohong Wang. System and Method for Rapid Face Recognition. US Patent app. 20140478. July 2014.

Armin Kappeler, Haiguang Li, **Michael Iliadis**, Haohong Wang. Method and Apparatus for Video Sequential Alignment. US Patent app. 20131543. December 2013.

Michael Iliadis, Haohong Wang. A new Image Classification Scheme based on Non-Linear function learning. Chinese Patent app. 20131184. December 2013.